Register of the American Children's Fund Records, 1923-1950
Hoover Institution Archives
American Children's Fund Records
1923-1950
XX511
American Children's Fund
48 manuscript boxes (7.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, financial records, and printed matter, relating to funding of the Boy Scouts, Girl Scouts, Boys' Clubs of America and other organizations carrying out work in the areas of child health and welfare in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Microfilm use only.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (49 reels).
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, financial records, and printed matter, relating to funding of the Boy Scouts, Girl Scouts, Boys' Clubs of America and other organizations carrying out work in the areas of child health and welfare in the United States.
Access Points
Boy Scouts.; Girl Scouts.; Boys' Clubs of America.; Child welfare--United States.; Child health services--United States.; Health.; Charities--United States.; United States.
Container List
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Directors File, 1920-1950. (Box No. 1-6.)
  Correspondence and minutes of meetings, relating to activities of the Directors. Includes correspondence of Herber Hoover, Chairman. Arranged by physical form
  - Correspondence (Box 1.)
    - Baker, George Barr, 1923-1935 (Folder 1)
    - Barnes, Julius, 1923-1937 (Folder 2)
    - Beeuwkes, Henry, 1936-1950 (Folder 3)
    - Farrand, Livinston, 1938-1942 (Folder 4)
    - Flesh, Edward, 1923-1937 (Folder 5)
    - Galpin, Perrin, 1932-1950 (Folder 6)
    - Goodrich, James P., 1923-1940 (Folder 7)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1923-1950 (Folder 8)
    - Lane, Gertrude, 1920-1924 (Folder 9)
    - McGarrah, Gates
      - 1923-1929 (Folder 10)
      - 1930-1940 (Folder 11)
    - Meier, Hugh, 1950 (Folder 12)
    - Meloney, William, Mrs., 1922-1940 (Folder 13)
    - Page, Frank C., 1935-1950 (Box 2., Folder 1)
    - Rickard, Edgar, 1924-1950 (Folder 2)
    - Sawtelle, Raymond, 1923-1936 (Folder 3)
    - Schroeder, Louis, 1929-1938 (Folder 4)
    - Shattuck, Edwin, 1923-1950 (Folder 5)
    - Smith, H. Alexander, 1934-1950 (Folder 6)
    - Strauss, Lewis L., 1924-1950 (Folder 7)
    - Warburg, Felix, 1923-1933 (Folder 8)
    - White, John B., 1938-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Meetings file. Includes minutes, correspondence and memoranda
    - General
      - 1923 September 26 (Folder 10)
      - 1924 March 3 (Folder 11)
      - 1925 February
        - 18 (Folder 12)
        - 26 (Folder 13)
      - 1926 February 17 (Folder 14)
      - 1927
        - February 16 (Folder 15)
        - April 6 (Folder 16)
      - 1928 (Box 3.)
        - February 23 (Folder 1)
        - March 6 (Folder 2)
      - 1929
        - February 20 (Folder 3)
        - May
          - 20 (Folder 4)
          - 27 (Folder 5)
          - 29 (Folder 6)
        - December 19 (Folder 7)
      - 1930 February 19 (Folder 8)
      - 1931
        - February 18 (Folder 9-11)
        - December 1 (Folder 12)
      - 1932 March 8 (Box 4., Folder 1)
      - 1933
        - February 23 (Folder 2)
        - March 3 (Folder 3)
      - 1934 February 21 (Folder 4)
      - 1935
        - February 20 (Folder 5)
        - April 9 (Folder 6)
        - June 11 (Folder 7)
        - August 13 (Folder 8)
      - 1936
        - February 19 (Folder 9)
        - September 9 (Box 5., Folder 1)
        - October
          - 6 (Folder 2)
          - 7 (Folder 3)
          - 23 (Folder 4)
      - 1937
        - February
          - 4 (Folder 5)
          - 17 (Folder 6)
        - November 15 (Folder 7-8)
      - 1938
        - February 16 (Folder 9)
        - May 12 (Folder 10)
      - 1939
        - February 23 (Folder 11)
        - March 9 (Folder 12)
      - 1940 December 4 (Folder 13)
    - Executive Committee (Box 6.)
      - 1937 June 28 (Folder 1)
      - 1938 December 6 (Folder 2)
      - 1942
        - June 26 (Folder 3)
        - October 6 (Folder 4)
      - 1943
        - January 6 (Folder 5)
        - June 10 (Folder 6)
      - 1944
        - March 24 (Folder 7)
        - June 7 (Folder 8)
      - 1947 March 27 (Folder 9)
      - 1949 April 5 (Folder 10)
      - 1950
        - January 18 (Folder 11)
        - March 11 (Folder 12)
- Office File, 1920-1953. (Box No. 6-20.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial records, minutes of meetings, printed matter and other materials. Arranged alphabetically by physical form and thereunder by subject
  - Appeals from U.S. organizations for funds
    - 1930-1943 (Box 6., Folder 13)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 14)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 15)
    - 1946-1953 (Box 7., Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General. Inquiries and requests, 1944-1952 (Folder 2)
    - Albanian-American School of Agriculture, 1927-1928 (Folder 3)
    - American Camping Association, 1937-1941 (Folder 4)
    - American Council on Education. American Youth Commission, 1942 (Folder 5)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1931-1947 (Folder 6)
    - American Institute of the City of New York, 1937 (Folder 7)
    - American Law Institute (Youth Authority Program), 1947-1948 (Folder 8)
    - American Red Cross, 1931-1943 (Folder 9)
    - Antioch College (Health Education)
      - 1936-1937 (Folder 10)
      - 1937-1939 (Box 8., Folder 1)
    - Baker Foundation (Judge Baker Center), 1931-1938 (Folder 2)
    - Bankers Club, 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
    - Baxter Seminary
      - 1930-1931 (Folder 4)
      - 1931-1935 (Folder 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 6)
      - 1936-1939 (Folder 7)
      - 1941-1953 (Folder 8)
    - Big Brother Movement, 1936 (Folder 9)
    - Boys' and Girls' Newspaper, 1935 (Folder 10)
    - Breining & Company, 1950 (Folder 11)
    - Camp Fire Girls, 1930-1948 (Folder 12)
    - Child Welfare League of America, 1936-1945 (Box 9., Folder 1)
    - Christodora House, 1936 (Folder 2)
    - Clark, Bert, 1921-1939 (Folder 3)
    - Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe, 1945-1949 (Folder 4)
    - Crusade for Children, 1933 (Folder 5)
    - Educational Alliance, 1944 (Folder 6)
    - Ford, James, 1939 (Folder 7)
    - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled, 1945 (Folder 8)
    - International Migration Service, 1926-1930 (Folder 9)
    - John Price Jones Corporation, 1942, 1944 (Folder 10)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund, 1934 (Folder 11)
    - Junior Achievement, Inc., 1929-1931 (Folder 12)
    - Kellogg, W. K., 1941 (Folder 13)
    - Leblond, C. P., 1942 (Folder 14)
    - Lutz, Ralph H., 1939 (Folder 15)
    - Metz-Braun Agency, 1923-1940 (Box 10., Folder 1)
    - Mills College, 1930 (Folder 2)
    - Murphy, G. M. & Company, 1936 (Folder 3)
    - National Amateur Athletic Federation. Women's Division
      - 1924-1926 (Folder 4)
      - 1926-1932 (Folder 5)
      - 1935-1937 (Folder 6)
      - 1938-1941 (Folder 7)
    - National Information Bureau, 1942 (Folder 8)
    - National Institute of Health
      - 1931-1932 (Folder 9)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 10)
    - National Recreation Association, 1943 (Folder 11)
    - New York Trust Company, 1938 (Folder 12)
    - Sage (Russell) Foundation, 1945 (Folder 13)
    - Sawtelle, Raymond, 1936-1943 (Folder 14)
    - Shattuck, Bangs, and Davis, 1941-1952 (Folder 15)
    - United Service Organizations, 1942 (Folder 16)
    - United States. Department of Commerce, 1935-1939 (Folder 17)
    - United States Society, 1936 (Box 11., Folder 1)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1934-1935 (Folder 2)
    - Westtown 1929 Fund, 1930 (Folder 3)
    - Wood (Leonard) Leprosy Fund, 1930-1932 (Folder 4)
    - Young Men's Christian Associations, 1930-1939 (Folder 5)
    - Young Women's Christian Associations, 1930-1931 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 7)
  - Cross references (Folder 8)
  - Dissolution documents
    - 1939 (proposed) (Folder 9)
    - 1949 (Folder 10)
    - 1950 (Folder 11)
  - Financial records
    - General
      - General, 1923-1950 (Folder 12)
      - Chase National Bank
        - 1929-1940 (Folder 13)
        - 1941-1950 (Folder 14)
      - Deloitte, Plender, Griffiths and Company, 1929-1950 (Folder 15)
      - Mechanics and Metals National Bank, 1923 (Folder 16)
    - Annual filing fees (State of Delaware), 1923-1949 (Box 12., Folder 1)
    - Audit report, 1924 (Folder 2)
    - Balance sheets
      - 1923-1924 (Folder 3)
      - 1924 (Folder 4)
      - 1926 (Folder 5)
      - 1943 (Folder 6)
      - 1945 (Folder 7)
      - 1946 (Folder 8)
      - 1947 (Folder 9)
      - 1948 (Folder 10)
      - 1949 (Folder 11)
    - Financial reports
      - 1924-1928 (Folder 12)
      - 1929 (Folder 13)
      - 1930-1934 (Folder 14)
      - 1935 (Box 13., Folder 1)
      - 1936 (Folder 2)
      - 1937 (Folder 3)
      - 1938 (Folder 4)
      - 1939 (Folder 5)
      - 1940 (Folder 6)
      - 1941 (Folder 7)
      - 1942 (Folder 8)
      - 1943 (Folder 9)
      - 1944 (Folder 10)
      - 1945 (Folder 11)
      - 1946 (Folder 12)
      - 1947 (Folder 13)
      - 1948 (Folder 14)
      - 1949 (Folder 15)
      - 1950 (Folder 16)
    - Luncheon expenses, 1926-1950 (Folder 17)
    - Receipts and expenditures
      - 1923-1938 (Folder 18)
      - 1923-1938 (Box 14., Folder 1)
      - 1923-1945 (Folder 2)
      - 1923-1946 (Folder 3)
      - 1923-1947 (Folder 4)
      - 1923-1948 (Folder 5)
      - 1923-1950 (Folder 6)
    - Securities, 1949 (Folder 7)
    - Signatures (Folder 8)
    - Statement of cash receipts and disbursements and statement of surplus, 1935-1940 (Folder 9)
    - Treasurer's report, 1924 (Folder 10)
  - Founding documents
    - By-laws (Folder 11)
    - Certificates of incorporation, resolutions and other founding documents (Folder 12)
    - Memorandum on the origin of funds, 1939 December 7 (Folder 13)
  - Insurance policies (Folder 14)
  - Letterhead stationery (Folder 15)
  - List of directors and officers (Folder 16)
  - Meetings file
    - 1923 September 26
      - Minutes (Folder 17)
      - Proxy for original corporators (Folder 18)
      - Waiver of notice (Folder 19)
    - 1924 February 20
      - Correspondence (Folder 20)
      - Minutes (Folder 21)
      - Report of Directors (Folder 22)
    - 1925 February 18
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Agenda (Folder 24)
      - Directors report (Folder 25)
      - Minutes (Folder 26)
      - Proxy forms (Folder 27)
    - 1927 February 16
      - General (Folder 28)
      - Agenda (Folder 29)
      - Directors report (Box 15., Folder 1)
      - Minutes (Folder 2)
    - 1928 February 23
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Agenda (Folder 4)
      - Financial report (Folder 5)
      - Minutes (Folder 6)
    - 1929 February 20
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Agenda (Folder 8)
      - Financial report (Folder 9)
      - Minutes (Folder 10)
    - 1930 February 19
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Agenda (Folder 12)
      - Financial report (Folder 13)
      - Minutes (Folder 14)
    - 1931 February 18
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Agenda (Folder 16)
      - Financial report (Folder 17)
      - Minutes (Folder 18)
    - 1932 February 17
      - General (Folder 19)
      - Agenda (Folder 20)
      - Financial report (Folder 21)
      - Minutes (Folder 22)
    - 1933 February 23
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Agenda (Folder 24)
      - Financial report (Folder 25)
      - Minutes (Folder 26)
    - 1934 February21
      - General (Folder 27)
      - Agenda (Folder 28)
      - Financial report (Folder 29)
      - Minutes (Folder 30)
    - 1935 February 20
      - General (Folder 31)
      - Agenda (Box 16., Folder 1)
      - Financial report (Folder 2)
      - Minutes (Folder 3)
    - 1936 February 19
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Agenda (Folder 5)
      - Financial report (Folder 6)
      - Minutes (Folder 7)
    - 1937 February 17
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Agenda (Folder 9)
      - Financial report (Folder 10)
      - Minutes (Folder 11)
      - Proxy forms (Folder 12)
    - 1938 February 16
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Agenda (Folder 14)
      - Minutes (Folder 15)
      - Proxy forms (Folder 16)
    - 1939 February 23
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Agenda (Folder 18)
      - Financial report (Folder 19)
      - Minutes (Folder 20)
      - Proxy forms (Folder 21)
    - 1940 February 21
      - General (Folder 22)
      - Minutes (Folder 23)
    - 1950
      - April 12
        - General (Folder 24)
        - Minutes (Folder 25)
        - Proxy forms (Folder 26)
      - December 4
        - General (Folder 27)
        - Agenda (Folder 28)
        - Financial report (Folder 29)
        - Minutes (Box 17., Folder 1)
        - Proxy forms (Folder 2)
  - Membership file
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - A-B (Folder 3)
        - C (Folder 4)
        - D-G (Folder 5)
        - H-O (Folder 6)
        - P-R (Folder 7)
        - S-V (Folder 8)
        - W-Z (Folder 9)
      - Possible candidates (Box 18., Folder 1)
    - Invitations and acceptances (Folder 2)
    - List of members (Folder 3)
  - Printed matter
    - Collected by the American Children's Fund (Folder 4-6)
    - Collected by the American Children's Fund (Box 19., Folder 1-3)
    - Referring to the American Children's Fund
      - General
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Copyright and royalty statements (Folder 5)
        - Copyright and royalty statements (Box 20., Folder 1)
      - Bane, Suda and Lutz, Ralph H., editors
        - The Blockade of Germany After the Armistice, 1918-1919, Stanford University Press, 1942 (Folder 2)
        - Organization of American Relief in Europe, 1918-1919, Stanford University Press, 1944 (Folder 3-4)
      - Galpin, Perrin, "A.R.A. Association," 1944 March 3 (Folder 5)
      - Rickard, Edgar, "The New Day for Children," New York Herald Tribune, 1931 April 26 (Folder 6)
  - Subject file
    - Name change from American Relief Administration Children's Fund. Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Folder 7)
    - Office equipment and furniture. Memorandum and report, 1935, 1946 (Folder 8)
    - Statutory representation. Correspondence, 1924-1949 (Folder 9)
  - Tax return file, 1937-1951 (Folder 10)
- Subject File, 1930-1950. (Box No. 21-26.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter and other materials. Arranged alphabetically by physical form and thereunder by subject
  - Allied Jewish Campaign, 1930 (Box 21., Folder 1)
  - American Child Health Association (Folder 2)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children (Folder 3)
  - Baxter Seminary (Tennessee) (Folder 4)
  - Boys Brotherhood Program (Folder 5)
  - Boys Clubs of America
    - General
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
        - Armstrong, David 1942 (Folder 7)
        - Bates, Sanford, 1937-1940 (Folder 8)
        - Galpin, Perrin, 1936-1945 (Folder 9)
        - Hall, Walter, 1937-1938 (Folder 10)
        - Hall, William E., 1936-1941 (Folder 11)
        - Harriman, E. Roland, 1941 (Folder 12)
        - Hoover, Herbert C., 1944 (Folder 13)
        - Kirkland, J. B., 1936-1940 (Folder 14)
        - Schroeder, Louis C., 1936-1937 (Folder 15)
        - Vincent, George, 1936 (Folder 16)
        - Wilbur, Ray L., 1937 (Folder 17)
      - Printed matter
        - General (Folder 18)
        - General (Box 22., Folder 1)
        - Boys Club Bulletin, 1937-1950 (Folder 2)
        - Boys Club Quarterly, 1938-1939 (Folder 3)
        - Health Manual, 1937-1938 (Folder 4)
        - Program Service
          - 1939 (Folder 5)
          - 1940 (Folder 6)
          - 1940-1941 (Folder 7)
      - Reports
        - Activities reports
          - 1937 (Folder 8)
          - 1938-1940 (Box 23., Folder 1)
        - Annual reports, 1937-1947 (Folder 2)
    - Budget, 1936-1944 (Folder 3)
    - Building projects
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Bronze plaques (Folder 5)
      - Locations
        - Alabama - Montgomery, 1941 (Folder 6)
        - California
          - Hollywood, 1942 (Folder 7)
          - San Diego, 1941 (Folder 8)
        - Idaho - Lewiston, 1950 (Folder 9)
        - North Carolina - Concord, 1948 (Folder 10)
        - Pennsylvania
          - Allentown, 1942 (Folder 11)
          - Harrisburg, 1948 (Folder 12)
        - Texas
          - Fort Worth, 1947 (Folder 13)
          - Laredo, 1941 (Folder 14)
          - Paris, 1941 (Folder 15)
          - River Oaks, 1950 (Folder 16)
    - Conventions
      - 1937 May 10-13 (Folder 17)
      - 1938 May 16-19 (Folder 18)
      - 1942 May 4-7 (Folder 19)
      - 1946 April 29 -May 2 (Folder 20)
      - 1947 May 8 (Folder 21)
    - Dinner, 1944 May 4 (Folder 22)
    - Financial assistance from the American Children's Fund (Box 24., Folder 1-3)
    - Health
      - Health Education Program
        - 1939 (Folder 4)
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 5)
      - Health Program (Folder 6)
      - Manual. Correspondence relating to, 1939 (Folder 7)
    - Juvenile delinquency (Folder 8)
    - Pre-Service Training Plan, 1943 (Folder 9)
    - Publicity (Folder 10)
    - Victory Program (Box 25., Folder 1)
  - Bureau for Intercultural Education (Folder 2)
  - Camp Fire Girls (Folder 3)
  - Catholic child education and health programs, 1930 (Folder 4)
  - Chicago Boys Club (Folder 5)
  - Child Welfare League (Folder 6)
  - Dental health (Folder 7)
  - Garon, Willie (Folder 8)
  - Judge Baker Foundation Fund (Folder 9)
  - Mills College
    - Appropriations
      - 1934 (Folder 10)
      - 1935-1939 (Folder 11)
    - Reports, publications (Folder 12)
  - National Amateur Athletic Federation. Women's Division (Box 26., Folder 1-2)
  - National Health Council (Folder 3)
  - National Recreation Conference, 1932 (Folder 4)
  - Newspaper for boys and girls in America, Proposed (Folder 5)
  - Osborne Association, Inc. (Folder 6)
  - Pediatric Foundation (Folder 7)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (Folder 8)
  - Porto Rico Child Health Committee (Folder 9)
  - President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1929-1935 (Folder 10)
  - Refugees - Turkey - Istanbul (Folder 11)
  - School of Social Work, Atlanta University (Folder 12)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1929-1932 (Folder 13)
- Boy Scouts of America, 1922-1956. (Box No. 26-40.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, fianancial records, minutes of meetings, printed matter and other materials. Relates to operations of the Boy Scouts of America and the funding received from the American Children's Fund. Arranged alphabetically by physical form and thereunder by subject
  - Constitution and by-laws (Box 26., Folder 14)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1922-1924 (Folder 15)
      - 1929-1931 (Folder 16)
      - 1932-1934 (Box 27., Folder 1)
      - 1934-1935 (Folder 2)
      - 1936-1942 (Folder 3)
      - 1949 (Folder 4)
    - Brouha, Lucien
      - 1943 (Folder 5)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 6)
    - Fawcett, William, 1947-1948 (Folder 7)
    - Fretwell, Elbert, 1943-1947 (Folder 8)
    - Goodman, E. Urner, 1944-1946 (Folder 9)
    - Hall, Lewis W., 1943-1946 (Folder 10)
    - Haysbert, Harry H., 1945-1950 (Folder 11)
    - Higgins, Donald M., 1949-1950 (Folder 12)
    - Ohta, James, 1944 (Folder 13)
    - Van Orden, 1944 (Folder 14)
    - West, James E., 1936, 1941-1943 (Folder 15)
    - Wickhorst, Frank, 1944 (Folder 16)
    - Wilcox, H. B., 1935-1939 (Folder 17)
  - Financial records
    - General (Folder 18-19)
    - Appropriations, receipts for payments, 1949 (Box 28., Folder 1)
    - Audit, 1943 March (Folder 2)
    - Expenses, 1936-1950 (Folder 3)
  - Gifts file. Correspondence and memoranda relating to gifts for staff at Christmas, 1943-1949 (Folder 4)
  - Meetings file
    - General
      - 1944 June 21 (Folder 5)
      - 1950
        - March 17 (Folder 6)
        - December 13 (Folder 7)
    - Committee of Operations, 1943 May 19 (Folder 8)
    - National Council
      - 1936 May 21-22 (Folder 9)
      - 1941 May 16-17 (Folder 10)
      - 1943
        - May 20 (Folder 11)
        - November 13 (Folder 12)
      - 1944 May 17 (Folder 13)
      - 1945 May 17 (Folder 14)
      - 1946 May 16-17 (Folder 15)
      - 1947 May 27-28 (Folder 16)
      - 1948, 1956 (Folder 17)
    - Program Committee
      - 1945
        - October 16 (Folder 18)
        - October 17 (Folder 19)
      - 1947 March 19 (Folder 20)
    - Regional Committee
      - 1947 November 1 (Folder 21)
      - 1948 October 29-30 (Folder 22)
  - Printed matter
    - General (Folder 23-25)
    - General (Box 29., Folder 1-5)
    - General (Box 30., Folder 1)
    - Bulletin, 1938, No. 7 (Folder 2)
    - Health and Safety
      - 1936-1940 (Folder 3)
      - 1941-1944 (Folder 4)
      - 1945-1950 (Folder 5)
      - 1947-1951 (Folder 6)
    - The National and World Jamborees in Pictures, 1937 (Folder 7)
    - Scouting
      - 1936-1939 (Folder 8)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 31., Folder 1)
      - 1942-1944 (Folder 2)
      - 1947-1949 (Folder 3)
  - Stationery (Folder 4)
  - Subject file
    - General (Folder 5-8)
    - Aeronautics and aviation (Folder 9)
    - Aquatics (Folder 10)
    - Boy scouts (Box 32.)
      - Belgium (Folder 1)
      - France - Paris (Folder 2)
      - Great Britain (Folder 3)
      - Lithuania (Folder 4)
      - United States
        - General - Afro-American
          - General
            - 1944-1947 (Folder 5)
            - 1947-1949 (Folder 6)
          - Maise, Fred (Folder 7)
        - Connecticut
          - Bristol Council (Folder 8)
          - Madison (Folder 9)
        - New York - White Plains (Folder 10)
    - Cooperative summer camps (Folder 11)
    - Crampton, C. Ward (Folder 12)
    - Crutches (Folder 13)
    - Drug shortage in the U.S., 1942 (Folder 14)
    - Etiquette book. Correspondence and clippings, 1940 (Folder 15)
    - Fatalities, 1942 (Folder 16)
    - First aid (Folder 17)
    - Fortieth Anniversary Crusade (Folder 18)
    - Galpin, Perrin (Folder 19-20)
    - Grant Foundation (Folder 21)
    - Harcher, Harry (Folder 22)
    - Head, Walter W. (Folder 23)
    - Health and Safety Committee (Box 33.)
      - General (Folder 1-2)
      - Appointments file (Folder 3)
      - Correspondence
        - Bushnell, Mart, 1947-1949 (Folder 4)
        - Crampton, C. Ward, 1942-1945 (Folder 5)
        - Emerson, Haven, 1943 (Folder 6)
        - Farrand, Livingston, 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
        - Gallagher, J. Rowell, 1945-1947 (Folder 8)
        - Galpin, Perrin
          - 1936-1945 (Folder 9)
          - 1946-1948 (Folder 10)
        - Goodwin, David, 1942 (Folder 11)
        - Hiscock, Ira, 1936-1946 (Folder 12)
        - Hooker, Ransom, 1935-1948 (Folder 13)
        - Kiphuth, Robert, 1942-1946 (Folder 14)
        - Lawrence, William E., 1942-1950 (Folder 15)
        - Lister, C. B., 1942 (Folder 16)
        - Mills, Fred C.
          - 1936-1939 (Folder 17)
          - 1939-1940 (Box 34., Folder 1)
          - 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
          - 1943 (Folder 3-4)
          - 1944 (Folder 5)
          - 1944-1945 (Folder 6)
          - 1946-1950 (Folder 7)
        - Palmer, George T., 1935-1948 (Folder 8)
        - Rickenbacker, E. V., 1944 (Folder 9)
        - Schroeder, Louis C., 1936 (Folder 10)
        - Schuck, Arthur, 1936-1937 (Folder 11)
        - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1944 (Box 35., Folder 1)
      - List of members (Folder 2)
      - Manual (Folder 3)
      - Meetings file. Minutes, correspondence, reports, notes
        - 1935-1937 (Folder 4)
        - 1938-1942 (Folder 5)
        - 1943-1945 (Folder 6)
        - 1943 May 25 (Folder 7)
        - 1944
          - February 7 (Folder 8)
          - November 22 (Folder 9)
        - 1945
          - April 27 (Folder 10)
          - December 12 (Folder 11)
        - 1948 January 23 (Folder 12)
        - 1949 April 29 (Folder 13)
      - Subject file - Sulfanilamide for first aid use (Folder 14)
    - Health and Safety Program
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Financial records, 1936-1940 (Box 36., Folder 1)